Zuko Tetyana

64 Parklands Main Rd, Parklands 7441

Zuko.Tetyana@techyana.co.za



in linkedin.com/in/zuko-tetyana-43683a108



073 123 3330



https://techyana.github.io/ZukoTetyana_CV/

Summary

From selling vodacom sim cards as a registered RICA agent to helping everyday people open accounts at edcon stores through ExShift Marketing since 2012 to 2013. I gained first hand experience with engaging with people face to face and applying rules of encounter proven to work, to this day I carry those lessons and values that continue to help me become a better developed individual.

2014 - 2017 I took on studies in Information Technology and Computer Science where I excelled in Computer Programming and broke the college record for 2 consecutive years in Computer Programming and I believe I still hold it to this day. I've always believed my advantage was the education and exposure I received in High School 2005 - 2009, Hoerskool Voortrekker, I was top Student in Visual Art and Computer Application Technology. During this period of studying I had two casual Jobs, one at a lifestyle night lounge as a barman and the other in Co-Managing a Guest House where I picked up accounting and interpersonal skills, I also learned about the importance of documentation and record keeping of transactions - be it currency or and operations.

2018 I entered the corporate world and was very fortunate to find work at an internationally known company where I have learned so much and still am as I'm still there. I've been exposed to so much in terms of leadership, engaging and conducting meetings with renowned clients. I've also been fortunate enough to exercise my core skills at the company and my sword keeps getting sharper as my journey keeps unfolding new opportunities disguised as challenges.

I wish to further my studies as I've become serious about Software Development. I've started and registered my company using my passion and goals as my trade and form of practical education. I'm highly invested in personal development and I see it in my other brands that I've spread/invested my skills in.

Zuko Tetyana

https://techyana.co.za https://capelanet.co.za

Experience

Onsite Engineer

Ricoh South Africa

Jan 2018 - Present (3 years 9 months +)

Here is the life changing career I stepped into. It is a technology company that offers hardware and software products and services.

My duties range from Installations of the devices, troubleshooting software and hardware related issues. Updating of firmware and Java (SDK) and operating in-house print management software tools for big clients such as Sanlam, Santam, Glacier Financial Services where I've been assigned as a dedicated Onsite Engineer.

To this day there's still so much I've learned beyond my Job description.

Co Manager

Sunshine Lodge

Jan 2014 - Nov 2017 (3 years 11 months)

Guest House, Accommodation.

Book keeping, reservations and engaging with Travel Agents/Companies on a professional level.

Keeping daily records of transactions and operations for daily tasks.

Distributor

ExShift Marketing

Nov 2012 - Dec 2013 (1 year 2 months)

Sold Vodacom SIM Cards and Contract SIM in person to person sales.

Opening of store accounts at edcon stores.

Trainee

Edcon

Dec 2012 - Jun 2013 (7 months)

Education



NCV Certificate, Information Technology

Jan 2014 - Nov 2017

Hoerskool Voortrekker

Matric Certificate

2004 - 2009

Skills

programming and design • Research • GitHub • Web Design • HTML5 • SASS • C# • PHP • Microsoft SQL Server • TypeScript